# Jonathan Dyer

+1 208-351-7237 · jbdyer@alumni.cmu.edu · linkedin.com/in/jon-dyer/ · github.com/jondyer

Carnegie Mellon University alum with 4+ years of experience in software engineering and strong fundamentals in machine learning. Enjoys diving into complex systems and analyzing difficult problems. Experience and interest in distributed systems, machine learning, and technical AI alignment.

## **Skills**

Python, Perl, JavaScript, SQL, Java, Git, Docker, AWS, Jenkins, Linux, bash, Scrum/Kanban, TensorFlow, Scikit-learn, machine learning, neural networks, deep learning, NLP, NumPy, Pandas, data visualization, artificial intelligence, AI safety & alignment

## **Employment**

Tomorrow University of Applied Sciences, Remote | Learning Design and Research

May 2023 - Present

- Designed and authored data science and machine learning course materials for an edtech startup
- Built automated assessment pipelines that integrated generative LLMs
- Led class sessions and taught advanced techniques for data structures, algorithms, and AI

#### Grant Street Group, Remote | Full Stack Software Engineer

Jan 2020 - Dec 2022

- Developed efficient APIs and microservices to handle thousands of transactions per day
- Consolidated multiple workflows into a user-friendly tool, significantly improving productivity
- Upgraded legacy application frontend to modern Javascript frameworks including Vue.js
- Mentored new developers and team members during onboarding and project ramp-up

#### Carnegie Mellon, Pittsburgh, PA | Graduate Teaching Assistant

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

- Object Oriented Programming for Managers
- Introduction to Programming with Python

### MIO Partners, New York City, NY | **DevOps / InfoSec Intern**

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

- Designed and built a custom suite of 10+ intelligence tools for the information security team
- Created pipelines for standardizing deployment across application teams, saving hours per week

#### UPMC Enterprises, Pittsburgh, PA | Software Engineering Intern

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

- Implemented full-stack solutions to enhance reporting capabilities for existing clients
- Attained 100% test coverage for all code and actively contributed as a member of an Agile software development team

## **Education**

# Carnegie Mellon University | Heinz College

grad. Dec 2019

Master of Information Systems Management

## **University of Pittsburgh**

grad. Apr 2018

B.S. Mathematics, B.S. Computer Science, *GPA: 3.92/4.0 (summa cum laude)*Culver Award, 2018 — outstanding performance by a student of mathematics

Laura LaFave and Peter Hallet endowment, 2017— exceptional performance in mathematics

Chancellor's Scholarship, 2012 — highest academic award given to new students

# **Academic Projects & Research**

## <u>CMU Capstone — Highmark</u>

 ${\it Capstone\ Project\ @\ Carnegie\ Mellon\ University\ --\ Pittsburgh,\ PA}$ 

- Analyzed healthcare cost and outcome data including 1000s of complex data points
- Built a supervised learning model to evaluate healthcare outcomes in different populations and regions
- Presented findings and benchmarks to executives at Highmark, changing program trajectory

#### **Cognitive Systems Group**

Universität Bremen — Bremen, Germany

- Conducted research on computational approximation of convergent human creativity tasks
- Designed and implemented combinatorial algorithms to enhance computational models
- Developed hypotheses and successfully published multiple papers

### Coursework

MATHEMATICS: Graph Theory, Linear Algebra, Mathematical Cryptography, Probability Theory, Multivariable Calculus

COMPUTER SCIENCE: Algorithm Design, Algorithm Implementation, Applied Cryptography, Data Structures, Database Management,

Distributed Systems, Systems Programming, Internet of Things

MACHINE LEARNING: Data-Focused Python, Statistical Machine Learning, Data Science and Big Data, Unstructured Data Analytics